Sheet Metal Workers' International Association, Local 83; Records apap047
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Sheet Metal Workers International Association Local 83 Records
1892-1989
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Sheet Metal Workers' International Association. Local 82 (Albany, New York)
apap047
2 cubic ft.
The Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 83 Records document the day-to-day operations of the union from the years 1892-1984 using meeting minutes and other documents refrenced in the minutes including correspondence, treasurer's reports, newsletters and strike bulletins.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All materials in this collection were loaned to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by the Sheet Metal Workers' International Association, Local 83 for preservation photocopying in 1990.
Administrative History
Local 83 was organized in 1892 as an affiliate of the Tin, Sheet Iron and Cornice Worker's International Association. In 1903 this international organization merged with the Sheet Metal Workers National Alliance, creating the Amalgamated Sheet Metal Worker's International Alliance. The Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 83 was chartered on April 1, 1920 by the Amalgamated Sheet-Metal Workers International Alliance and then by the Sheet Metal Workers International Association on July 22, 1924. At that time, their jurisdiction spanned through Saratoga, Albany and Rensselaer Counties of New York. Schenectady County was added to their jurisdiction by 1930. The current jurisdiction covers the counties of: Albany, Clinton, Columbia, Greene, Hamilton, Montgomery, Rensselaer, Saratoga, Schenectady, Schoharie, Warren and Washington.[1]
Comprised of a group of highly skilled sheet metal workers, this union serves as both an educational institution that trains future sheet metal workers through a five year apprentice program and as a forum for grievances suffered by members.[2] As the local legislative body for all sheet metal workers in upstate New York, this organization is responsible for negotiating the length of workdays, the number of vacation days, the average pay and the overtime rate. It organizes strikes when conditions at a job site are deemed unsafe or unfair, supports families of those who are on strike, and fines those who break strike lines. This organization also determines which jobs fall under the job description of sheet metal workers. To achieve this, Local 83 coordinates with other labor unions that perform similar tasks such as the Boiler Makers Union or the Air Condition and Heating Union.
Notes
1. Press release, New York State Department of Labor, Steel Metal Workers Recruit Apprentices (Albany, NY, June 4, 2001), http://www.labor.state.ny.us/business_ny/apprenticeship_training/press_releases/smw_gcd3.htm (16 August 2002).
2. Landau, Mark B., Sheet Metal Workers Local Union #83 (Albany, NY, undated), http://hometown.aol.com/SMWIA83org/. (28 August 2002).
Scope and Contents
The Sheet Metal Worker's International Association, Local 83 collection documents the founding and daily activities of this organization from 1892-1984. In addition to the actual minutes, related materials that have been entered into the body of the minutes have been filed at the back of the folders. These related materials include correspondence, treasurer's reports and other documents referred to in the body of the minutes. The bulk of the business discussed within the minutes of Local 83 concerns grievance cases where the plaintiff was laid off unfairly.
The minutes found in the records of the Sheet Metal Workers International are photocopies from the original ledgers of this organization. At times the copies are difficult to read. This is especially true of the pre-1900 minutes as the words from the reverse side often obscured the already difficult penmanship. There is a gap in the minutes from 1909-1919.
The collection also includes newsletters a program from Local 83's 1987 dinner dance. Strike bulletins are included with the newsletters.
For additional labor collections in the Department, see the online subject guide for Labor.
Arrangement of the Collection
Series 1: Minutes and Related Materials, 1892-1908, 1920-1942, 1944-1949, 1951-1989, 2 cubic ft. Arranged Chronologically.
The minutes of the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 83 document the daily activities of this organization. Included within the minutes are Treasurers' reports, discussions of incoming correspondence, reports from the Grievance Committee that coordinates incoming grievances against both employers of members of Local 83 and fellow members of Local 83, reports from the Trial Committee that coordinate court cases against members of this organization and reports from the Testing Committee that creates and administers the examination given to apprentices at the culmination of their five year apprenticeship.
Schenectady, New York; Rensselaer County, New York; Labor; Sheet-metal; Unions, Labor; Labor union meetings; Albany (N.Y.); Saratoga (N.Y.); Rensselaer(N.Y.); Correspondence; Newsletters; Administrative records; Minutes; Financial Records; Tin, Sheet Iron and Cornice Worker's International Association; Sheet Metal Workers' International Association; Amalgamated Sheet Metal Workers; international alliance
- Minutes and Related Materials, 1892-1908, 1920-1942, 1944-1949, 1951-1989; 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Content Note
  The Sheet Metal Worker's International Association, Local 83 collection documents the founding and daily activities of this organization from 1892-1984. In addition to the actual minutes, related materials that have been entered into the body of the minutes have been filed at the back of the folders. These related materials include correspondence, treasurer's reports and other documents referred to in the body of the minutes. The bulk of the business discussed within the minutes of Local 83 concerns grievance cases where the plaintiff was laid off unfairly.
  The minutes found in the records of the Sheet Metal Workers International are photocopies from the original ledgers of this organization. At times the copies are difficult to read. This is especially true of the pre-1900 minutes as the words from the reverse side often obscured the already difficult penmanship. There is a gap in the minutes from 1909-1919.
  The collection also includes newsletters a program from Local 83's 1987 dinner dance. Strike bulletins are included with the newsletters.
  For additional labor collections in the Department, see the online subject guide for Labor.
  - Roll of Members, Minutes, 1892-1894 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1894 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1894-1898 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1898-1899 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1899-1901 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 5)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1901-1902 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1902-1904 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1904-1905 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1905-1907 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 9)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1907-1908 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 10)
  - Materials Related to Missing Minutes of 1912, List of Officers of Local 83, Minutes and Related Materials, 1920-1922 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1922-1925 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1925-1927 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 13)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1927-1929 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1929-1930 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1930 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1930-1931 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 17)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1931 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1931-1932 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1932-1933 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1933-1934 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 1934-1935 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 1935-1936 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 23)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1936-1938 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 24)
  - Minutes, 1938-1939 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1939-1940 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 26)
  - Minutes, 1940-1941 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 27)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1941-1942 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 28)
  - Minutes, 1944-1945 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 29)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1945-1946 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 30)
  - Minutes, 1946-1947 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 31)
  - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1948-1949 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 33)
  - Minutes, 1951-1952 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 34)
  - Minutes, 1952-1953 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 35)
  - Minutes, 1953-1954 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 36)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1954-1955 (Box 1 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 37)
  - Minutes, 1955-1956 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1957-1958 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1959-1960 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 5)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1960-1961 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 6)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1961-1962 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1963-1964 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 8)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1964 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 9)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1965 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 10)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1965-1966 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 11)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1966-1967 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 12)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1967-1968 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 13)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1968-1969 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 14)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 15)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1970-1971 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 23)
  - Minutes and Related Materials, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 24)
  - Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 26)
  - Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 27)
  - Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 28)
  - Dinner Dance, 1987 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 29)
  - Newsletters, 1968-1980 (Box 2 (1-Minutes and Related Materials), Folder 30)